Thomas Koch

Senior Mobile Game Developer

Summary

Highly skilled and passionate Senior Mobile Developer with over 10 years of experience in mobile game development, specializing in Unity, Android, and Flutter technologies utilizing the Agile/Scrum development process. With expertise in team leadership, client communication, and requirement gathering contributed to many mobile applications.

Contract

tkoch9114@gmail.com

<u>LinkedIn</u>

Web Site

+1 (516) 368-1811

Islip, NY, United States

Skills

C#

JavaScript

Unity

C++

Cocos

Dart

Flutter

Java

Kotlin

Python

.NET Core

Firebase

Node.js

MySQL

PostgreSQL

SQLite

MongoDB

Education

Rochester Institute of Technology

April 2010 – July 2014 Rochester, NY, United States

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

Work Experience

Senior Unity Engineer

INFINITY-UP Full-time

May 2020 - Present

Dover, DE, United States Remote

- Project flexibility to speed up the process and split the work between teams.
- Remake a game with Unity technology, push it to the limits with visuals and physics that are
 possible in multiplayer, and get the new battle royale mode.

Unity Game Developer

The NineHertz Full-time

June 2018 – May 2020

Cincinnati, OH, United States Hybrid

- Reuse modules in other systems or projects.
- Involved in implementing game mechanics and optimizing performance, and also collaborated with other team members, such as game designers and artists, to ensure that the game meets both the creative and technical requirements.
- Provided support to the team whenever needed & help them understand their task

Mobile Developer

Roonyx Full-time

March 2017 – June 2018

New York, NY, United States On-Site

- Designed a working prototype of a future client-facing application.
- Analyzed the existing dispatch system and determined what endpoints will have to be created to exchange the needed data with the mobile app and used Flutter to cover both platforms.
- Complete a blockchain application project another engineering group didn't complete.
- Deliver features and fix them rapidly on a product that is recently released.

Unity Developer

KAPPS Full-time

September 2014 – March 2017

Kyiv, Kyiv, Ukraine Remote

- Successfully designed, developed, and deployed different Editor tools to improve work efficiency for animators, level designers, artists, game designers, etc.
- Adapted Legacy Editor tools from 2D to 3D and the new workflow of the team.
- Unity Editor integrated UI which dynamically tracks which scene or assets are affected by repository users.
- Custom tree graph editor with tons of project-related adjustments.